Hey, everyone, and welcome.
皆さん、こんにちは。
Today, we're going to unlock a super simple but really powerful secret to making your English
今日は、英会話をより良くする シンプルで強力な秘密を紹介します。
conversations so much better.
これで会話が格段に良くなります。
By the end of this, you're going to be a pro. Let's dive in.
最後には、あなたもプロになれます。 さあ、始めましょう。
So let's start with this question right here. Are you hungry?
まずはこの質問から始めましょう。 お腹が空いていますか？
Super simple, right?
とてもシンプルですね。
And honestly, questions like this, they're your secret key to starting a conversation
実際、こういった質問が会話を 始めるための秘密の鍵です。
with pretty much anyone, anywhere.
ほぼ誰にでも、どこでも使えます。
All right, here's our mission for today.
さて、今日のミッションです。
And I want you to think of it kind of like a video game.
これをゲームのように考えてください。
We're going to level up through six different stages, and by the end, you'll unlock that
6つのステージをクリアして、 最後には質問の達人になりましょう。
final achievement, becoming a question master. Ready to play?
準備はいいですか？ さあ、始めましょう。
Let's go. Alright, welcome to level one, the question magic trick.
レベル1へようこそ、質問の魔法の技です。
This is like the main spell for everything we're about to learn.
これは、これから学ぶ全ての 基本的な呪文です。
And trust me, it is so, so easy.
信じてください、とても簡単です。
Okay, so this magic trick, it's super simple.
この魔法の技は、非常にシンプルです。
You take a normal sentence, right, like he is rich.
普通の文を取ります。例えば、 彼は裕福です。
Step one, you just find that B verb. In this case, it's is.
ステップ1は、B動詞を見つけること。 この場合は「is」です。
Step two, you grab it and move it all the way to the front.
ステップ2は、それを文の先頭に移動します。
And for step three, you just pop a question mark at the end. And boom!
ステップ3は、文の最後に 疑問符を付けること。はい、完了です！
Is he rich? You just turned a statement into a question.
「彼は裕福ですか？」と、 文を質問に変えました。
It really does work every time. Awesome job on level one.
これが毎回うまくいくんです。 レベル1、お疲れ様でした。
You've totally learned the spell.
呪文を完全に習得しましたね。
So now, for level two, we're going to figure out how to answer when somebody asks you
次はレベル2です。 誰かに質問されたときの答え方を学びます。
a question. Let's keep building up those skills.
スキルをさらに磨いていきましょう。
Okay, so just imagine someone walks up to you and asks this question on the slide.
例えば、誰かがこのスライドの質問を あなたに聞いてきたとします。
Are you from New York? So what do you say?
「ニューヨーク出身ですか？」 あなたは何と答えますか？
Well, there's a really specific but super easy pattern you can follow.
実は、すごくシンプルなパターンがあります。
Check it out. Here's the pattern.
こちらがそのパターンです。
If your answer is yes, all you have to say is, yes, I am. So simple.
もし答えが「はい」なら、 「はい、そうです」と言えばOKです。
And if it's no, you can say, no, I am not, or to sound a little more natural, you can
「いいえ」の場合は、「いいえ、そうではありません」と言うか、 もっと自然に「いいえ、そうじゃない」と言えます。
use the contraction and just say, no, I'm not. It's that easy.
それだけで簡単です。
You've got this. Okay. Here's a super important tip, a secret even.
あなたならできます。 さて、ここで重要なヒントです。
You know, some people try to make a contraction like ammit, but
一部の人は「ammit」のように 短縮形を作ろうとしますが、
you gotta watch out cuz it's a total trap.
それは完全に罠です。
No, I ammit is just never, ever used in English.
「No, I ammit」は英語では 決して使われません。
Seriously, just remember that one little rule and
この小さなルールを覚えておけば、
you'll sidestep that trap every single time.
その罠を毎回回避できます。
Fantastic, you have totally crushed level two.
素晴らしい、レベル2を完全にクリアしました。
Now it's time to expand your superpowers a bit.
次はあなたのスーパーパワーを 少し広げる時間です。
So for level three, we're gonna learn how to ask questions about other people.
レベル3では、他の人について 質問する方法を学びます。
You know, your friends, your family, or even stuff around you.
友達や家族、周りのことについてです。
Alright, this slide is basically your guide for asking about other people.
このスライドは、他の人について 質問するためのガイドです。
Like if you ask, is he a baseball player? The answer is simple.
例えば、「彼は野球選手ですか？」と聞くと、 答えはシンプルです。
Yes he is, or no he isn't. And guess what?
「はい、そうです」または「いいえ、そうではありません」。 そして、グループや物についても同じパターンです。
The patterns are pretty much the same when you're talking about a group of people
「彼ら」や「それ」を使うときも同様です。
with they or a thing with it.
「いいえ」の場合は、選択肢があります。
And hey, for those no answers, you've got options.
「彼はそうではない」または「彼ではありません」と言えます。 どちらでも完璧です。
You can say he's not or he isn't. Other one is totally perfect.
素晴らしい進捗ですが、準備はいいですか？
You are doing so great, but are you ready?
ボスバトルの時間です。
It's time for The Boss Battle.
ここでは、最も難しい罠に挑みます。
This is where we're going to face the trickiest traps of all.
これをクリアすれば、本物の達人です。
Passing this proves you're a real master.
でも心配しないで、あなたならできます。
But don't worry, I know you can do this.
さて、これが大きな罠です。
Okay, here it is, the big trap.
誰かが「ジョンは教師ですか？」と聞いたとき、
When someone asks, is John a teacher?
「はい、ジョンです」と答えるのが自然に感じますよね？
It feels really natural to just answer, yes, John is, right?
しかし、ここが重要です。
But, and this is a big but.
英語では、名前を代名詞に置き換えなければなりません。
In English, you have to replace the name with a pronoun.
正しい答えは常に「はい、彼です」です。
This is a super, super important rule to remember.
これは非常に重要なルールです。
And to help you defeat that boss, here are your pronoun power-ups.
ボスを倒すために、代名詞のパワーアップを紹介します。
Just always remember this. A guy's name, like John, that becomes he.
男の名前、例えばジョンは「彼」になります。
A girl's name, like Emily, she becomes she.
女の名前、例えばエミリーは「彼女」になります。
If you've got two people, like George and Peter, they become they.
二人の人がいる場合、例えばジョージとピーターは「彼ら」になります。
And anything, like this book, or that house, becomes it.
何か、例えばこの本やあの家は「それ」になります。
Cut these down, and you'll nail it every time. You did it!
これを覚えておけば、毎回成功します。やったね！
You defeated the boss! You've learned all the skills!
ボスを倒しました！すべてのスキルを学びました！
So now it's time for the final challenge.
さあ、最後の挑戦の時間です。
A little pop quiz to test out your new superpowers.
新しいスーパーパワーを試すポップクイズです。
You ready for this? Alright, let's do this.
準備はいいですか？さあ、始めましょう。
I'm going to read the questions you see on the slide.
スライドに表示される質問を読みます。
Try to answer them out loud wherever you are.
どこにいても声に出して答えてみてください。
Number one, are you from Tokyo? Number two, is she a science teacher?
1番、あなたは東京出身ですか？ 2番、彼女は理科の先生ですか？
Number three, is Peter in Japan now?
3番、ピーターは今日本にいますか？
And hey, remember that pronoun rule we just talked about.
そして、さっき話した代名詞のルールを思い出して。
Number four, is math easy for you? And number five, is that your car?
4番、数学はあなたにとって簡単ですか？ 5番、それはあなたの車ですか？
Okay, let's see how you did. Time to check those answers.
さて、どうだったか見てみましょう。答えを確認します。
So for number three, did you remember to use he instead of Peter?
3番では、ピーターの代わりに「彼」を使いましたか？
I bet you did. And for numbers four and five, did you use it?
きっと使ったでしょう。4番と5番では「それ」を使いましたか？
And hey, even if you made a little mistake here or there, that's totally okay.
もし少し間違えても大丈夫です。
Seriously, the most important thing is that you tried.
本当に大事なのは、挑戦したことです。
Practice is what makes us better. You did a great job.
練習が私たちを成長させます。素晴らしい仕事でした。
You did it, you passed the final challenge.
あなたはやり遂げました、最終挑戦をクリアしました。
It's official, you are a question master.
公式に、あなたは質問マスターです。
Let's take a quick victory lap
さあ、勝利の周回をしましょう。
and just look back at everything you've accomplished today.
今日達成したことを振り返りましょう。
And think of this slide as your trophy.
このスライドをトロフィーだと思ってください。
This is your ultimate cheat sheet.
これはあなたの究極のチートシートです。
It's got every single question and answer pattern we went over today.
今日学んだすべての質問と答えのパターンが含まれています。
Keep this handy and you'll never be stuck for an answer again.
これを手元に置いておけば、答えに困ることはありません。
You totally earned this. Okay, so I've got one last question for you.
あなたはこれを完全に手に入れました。さて、最後の質問です。
Is English fun now?
今、英語は楽しいですか？
And I really hope you can use the new skills you just learned
新しく学んだスキルを使って、
to answer with a big confident, yes it is.
自信を持って「はい、楽しいです」と答えられることを願っています。
Keep practicing with this stuff and I promise you'll be amazed
このことを練習し続ければ、
at how much better your conversations get. You did amazing work today.
会話がどれだけ良くなるかに驚くことでしょう。今日は素晴らしい仕事をしました。